Sahil Ajmera

https://sahil-ajmera.github.io | sa7810@rit.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-ajmera-b6144092/ | https://github.com/Sahil-Ajmera | +1(646)571-9799

CAREER SUMMARY

Dedicated and versatile software engineer with one-year co-op experience in different domains handling different kinds of projects with skills in programming and building and maintaining software applications. Seeking an entry-level position as a Software Developer. Available - December 2019.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York

Expected December 2019

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.96 / 4.0

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Foundations of Algorithms, Introduction To Big Data, Foundations of Intelligent Systems, Introduction to Computing Security, Advanced Database Systems, Information Retrieval and Text Analytics

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal, Karnataka, India

Earned 2017

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

SKILLS

Certifications: Oracle Certified Professional JAVA SE6 Programmer, Microsoft Technical Associate for Cloud Fundamentals

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C#

Relational Database Management Systems: SQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle 11g

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, Materialize

Desktop Application Development: Qt

Orchestration Tools: Juju Charms, Ansible Playbooks

Source Control: Git

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Lenovo Software Development Co-op – Data Center Group Morrisville, North Carolina

August 2018 - Present

- Added features to Lenovo's RHHI offering by leading efforts on instantiation, configuration and validation of platforms like CloudForms, ManageIQ and Gitlab.
- Created a desktop application for ForkLift operators that gives information about the load they are carrying and the lane they are carrying that load to. (Presented at MWC - 2019)
- Created 3 Rapid Access Demos (RADs) as a means of proof of technology allowing customers and partners with remote testing of Lenovo Data Center solutions.
- Technologies used Python, C#, Juju Charms, Qt, MQTT, RHVM, CloudForms, ManageIQ, Ansible, Materialize, .NET

American Institutes For Research

Washington, District of Columbia

May 2018 – August 2018

Software Engineer Intern • Integrated existing workflow of Item Card report generation into workflow of Custom Pdf report generation so that statistics of items can also be printed while making a Custom Pdf Report.

- Diagnosed bugs and implemented new features as per client requirements.
- Decreased the time that will take in later development operations by documenting existing code.
- Technologies Used: C#, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, SQL, SQL Server

PROJECTS

Mobile App Review Classifier

June 2018 - August 2018

- Created 5 Naïve-Bayes classifiers to classify app reviews obtained from Google Play store as information giving, information seeking, bug report, feature request and displaying positive/negative/neutral sentiment.
- Created a web application that gives all the above information when an app review is input into the text field.
- Achieved F-measure values of 30%, 37%, 62.5%, 48.7%, 81.58% respectively for the 5 classifiers formed.
- Technologies Used: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask

Gender Recognition: Technique using PCA and GA

January 2017 - April 2017

- Achieved a 6% accuracy improvement over traditional gender recognition technique on the FERET dataset.
- Technologies Used: Python, MATLAB, WEKA